Thomas C. Hsu

Mobile: (732) 647-5373 | Email: thomaschsu@gmail.com | Holmdel, NJ

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/tomchsu | Portfolio: thomaschsu.github.io | GitHub: github.com/thomaschsu

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced Front-End Web Developer with a proven background in developing user-friendly websites and web applications. Well-versed in various programming languages including JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Node, and more. A proactive professional who enjoys systematically testing websites for bugs and debugging errors. Looking forward to applying my knowledge and expertise of web development to a like-minded company to ensure quality user interaction that produces optimal results.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Responsive Web Design, JSON
- Magento Ecommerce
- WordPress
- Node.js, Firebase
- Express

- GIT, GitHub
- Bootstrap
- APIs, AJAX
- CLI
- Microsoft Office Suite and Adobe Suite
- MySQL

APPLICATIONS BUILT

Goodmovies

- Lead Front-End Developer of group of three
- Website dedicated to finding movies based on rotten tomatoes ratings
- Ability to save favorite movies into Firebase
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Firebase, APIs, jQuery, Font Awesome

Liri - Node Application

- Front-End Developer
- Node application that uses Twitter, Spotify, and OMDB API to display information depending on what arguments
 you input
- Implemented in friendly UI. uses Counter
- JavaScript, APIs, Node, Node Modules

New York Times - Search

- Lead Front-End Developer of group of four
- A page that searches through NYT using queries and NYT API
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, APIs, jQuery

WORK EXPERIENCE

MRA International - Long Branch, NJ

March 2013 - February 2018

Website Administrator, Web Developer, IT Technician, Inside Sales Representative

- Took a lead role in the production and maintenance of a front end Magento and WordPress company website.
 Included implementing a PunchOut catalog, systematically testing the website for bugs, and managing the backend Magento catalog.
- Built and managed graphics for front end of website

- Provided client services in massive company project that required imaging thousands of laptops and desktops for Elizabeth school districts within tight time constraints.
- Repaired malfunctioning desktops and laptops and networked with customers as an inside sales representative.

DuPont – Parlin, NJ

June 2007 – August 2007 | May 2008 – August 2008 | June 2011 – July

2011

Manufacturing Technician LSE

- Assisted with processing, inspection and packaging of Cyrel Flexographic plates
- Distributed finished products
- Gained knowledge in patience and hard work

EDUCATION

Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey - New Brunswick, NJ

April 2018 – Current

Rutgers Coding Program - Full Stack Web Development

Rutgers the State University of New Jersey - New Brunswick, NJ

January 2012

School of Arts and Sciences | School of Information Technology and Informatics | Bachelor of Arts

Major: Information Technology and Informatics

Minor: Psychology